Patrick Cahel

Email: PatrickCahel@gmail.com Phone: (202) 999-6730

Four years in contracts administration honed my strong attention to detail and analytical skills; e.g., in issue spotting, enforcing compliance, using efficient communication, process improvement. I bring a problem-solving mindset and leadership potential, setting others up for success in operational and cost effectiveness and efficiency.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BE BE CLEANERS San Francisco garment care business

San Francisco, CA

Small Business Owner and Manager | December 2022 – January 2024

Revitalized a struggling business by better bookkeeping, using top dry-cleaning plants, and personalizing service.

• Digitized tracking of orders, services, invoices, and payments for immediate customer-sentiment and margin gains. Doubled customer base within a year.

CAI INTERNATIONAL, INC. \$1.9B Intermodal container leasing and sales company

San Francisco, CA

Legal Contracts Coordinator | March 2020 - October 2022

Reported to Chief Legal Officer. Drafted, coded, approved, and tracked hundreds of agreements. Key contributor for improved quality, turnaround time, regulatory compliance, and reliability of contracts for 12 offices worldwide.

CONTRACTS TEAM LEADERSHIP

- Led meticulous code-checking, review, troubleshooting, and approval of hundreds of contracts.
- Led team in contract analysis to align contracts for subsidiary integration upon Mitsubishi HC's acquisition of CAI.
- Improved efficiency by revising templates, giving guidance to peers on coding in proprietary Contract Lifecycle Management system interfacing with billing, supply, and accounting; reduced billing-cycle time and administrative costs by 50%.

CONTRACTS ADMINISTRATION, AUDITING, AND LEGAL COMPLIANCE MONITORING

- Researched statutes of multiple jurisdictions for reporting, fee, and filing compliance to maintain corporate legal standing.
- Drafted and fact-checked 170 unique legal agreements with Maersk, Hyundai, Hapag-Lloyd, and other major players, carefully researching profiles, legality, prior contracts, and historical data.
- Curated database housing live fact sheets for 1,500+ contracts, becoming the go-to POC for billing and operations.
- Strengthened collaboration between Legal Department and external auditing teams after gaining trust as an informed Subject Matter Expert on lease-finance agreements, resulting in smoother processing of audits.
- Enhanced contract intake by refining and increasing data points on 6 offer sheets, boosting average turnaround by 50%.
- Participated in onboarding negotiations for strategic accounts, B2B communications with outside legal teams.

Legal Contracts Assistant | February 2019 - March 2020

Eliminated a two-year backlog of unfiled, unsigned, incomplete contracts to support converting -20% YoY losses in 2018 to +16% YoY gains by YE 2019 – greatly boosting share value, attracting Mitsubishi HC acquisition in 2021.

- Reviewed 20 contracts per week, ultimately expediting execution by 60% with error-free coding for hundreds of criteria.
- Led special projects, such as single-handedly fact checking and preparing 1,000+ agreements for digitization in 6 weeks.
- Commended by Chief Human Resources Officer and CLO for fostering harmonious interdepartmental rapport.

UNIVERSITY GAMES, INC. \$5M Educational toy and game creator/producer

San Francisco, CA

Wholesale Order Entry Analyst | February 2018 – August 2018

Processed 200+ wholesale orders per month, logged client data, processed invoices and payments, created Work Orders and daily reports for Sales and Leadership. Oversaw manufacturer shipment tracking during senior manager's absence.

• Troubleshot order and delivery issues, concerns, and product returns with customers and retail stores across N. America.

BAIN & COMPANY Global management consulting firm

San Francisco, CA

Research Assistant | January 2018 - February 2018

Promoted to research, validate, and code data, including survey responses in strategic verticals, e.g., Retail and Healthcare. Gathered feedback from 500 hospitals and clinics across the US, improved a protocol to triple the collection success rate.

Office Assistant | November 2017 – January 2018

Entry-level Mail Room position distributing confidential documents for 100+ personnel across 4 floors of the Embarcadero Center. Routinely complimented by consultants and partners for speed, professionalism, and positive attitude.

EDUCATION AND MILITARY BACKGROUND

The George Washington University - Psychology; Brain & Cognition research assistant to Myeong-Ho Sohn, Ph.D.

U.S. ARMY, Sergeant E-5 – Third Infantry Division, Iraq, shop foreman, quality control officer, special assignments, led teams of up to 12, numerous awards and commendations for strategic and tactical excellence.